NAVEEN KUMAR.G

Room No.402, Site No.3,K No. 9/1/3 & 9,

2nd Main, 3rd Cross, Hongasandra, Begur Main Road, Bangalore-560068. E-Mail: naveengunakumar@gmail.com Mobile: 09688752015/09886707388

OBJECTIVE:

Seeking a Suitable position in Finance, Auditing and Accounting with an organization of repute where I can learn and contribute to the growth of the organization.

SPECIFICATIONS:

Accounts Payable, Accounts Receivable, Auditing, General Accounts, Inventory, Banking and Finalization.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Name of the Company	Designation	Period
Venkateshwara Hatcheries (P) Ltd - Bangalore	Officer Accounts	DECEMBER 2013 – OCTOBER 2017
Mindteck India Limited	Senior Executive Finance	OCTOBER 2017 - Till Date

Mindteck is an Indian company that provides product engineering solutions and IT services to several Fortune 100 companies, universities and government agencies. Mindteck has also been one of the founding members of The Atlas Online. Established in 1991; the company is headquartered at Bangalore. Sanjeev Kathpalia is the CEO and managing director of the company. It is a CMMI Dev Ver 1.3 Level 5 company.

EDUCATION QUALIFICATION:

Education	Name of the Board/University/Institute	Year of Pass
HSC	OXFORD HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL, UDUMALPET	2010
B.COM WITH COMPUTER APPLICATION	VIDHYASAGAR COLLEGE OF ARTS & SCIENCE,UDUMAI	2011-2013

SUMMARY OF SKILLS:

Achievement oriented accounting professional with <u>5.9 YEARS</u> of experience in accounting and finance across various verticals. Strong computer basics Ms Office, Internet, excellent multi-tasking organizational aptitude and proven ability to work in a highly competitive and fast paced environment.

CSI Computer Education - Faculty in the period of 2010-2012 (2 Years)

- ◆ Operating & Working Knowledge in MS Word, Tally, Oracle and ERP.
- ◆ Web Technology HTML
- ◆ Designing DTP(Photo Shop, Photo Maker)

Professional Experience (5.9 YEARS)

Accounting & Statutory:

- ➤ Book Keeping, Vouching and certification (Payment, Receipt, Journal, Debit/Credit Note, Bank Voucher and other accounting vouchers).
- > Consolidate of various Division/branch/locations financial activities.
- > Inter Branch, Inter Division & Inter Company activities of Inventory transfers, financial transactions.
- Associate & Group Companies Reconciliations.

Accounts Payable:

- ➤ Verifying of Supplier Bills (with all supporting documents like Indent, PO, GRN & Invoice) and Passing the Payments.
- ➤ Controlling the Supplier ageing and reconciliations with Supplier balance.
- ➤ Getting the confirmation of balance from Supplier on periodically.
- Monthly Provision entries for all prepaid and Expenses.
- ➤ GST purchase details verification.
- > Checking RCM for URD suppliers

Accounts Receivables:

- Ensuring the data entry/updating on daily basis.
- > Supervising the sales updating, Debtors balance on daily basis.
- ➤ Controlling the Credit limit and recovering the dues from credit customers.
- ➤ Getting the confirmation of balance from Debtors on periodically.
- ➤ Monthly Revenue unbilled & Excess Billing provision entries.
- Consolidating FPP project, MIS Report, Profitability, Revenue VS Budject on monthly basis.
- ➤ GST Customer sales verification.

GST Filing:

- ➤ Month GSTR-1 and GSTR-3 Filing.
- > ITC Claiming and Refund claiming process.
- ➤ Verifying GST Receivable and Payable account.
- ➤ GST Bank Online payment with Payable and receivable bifurcation.

Cash and Banking:

- Monitoring and controlling the cash and bank account transactions.
- > Petty cash maintaining.
- ➤ Bank Reconcilisation.
- Foreign Export and Import payment process, Bill of entry.
- > STPI,EOP and Export document filing.
- > Softex and FIRC consolidation.
- ➤ Bank, Supplier, Customer MIS consolidate.

Fixed Assets:

- ➤ Maintaining of Fixed Assets Register.
- > Updating the additional & deletions of fixed assets on time to time.

- > Calculation of depreciation as per the companies Act.
- ➤ Controlling the assets numbering systems and Handling the asset movements.

Inventory:

- ➤ Closing stock valuation.
- Passing provision entries.
- Reports for Balance Sheet format, Transfer pricing, Branch Sales and purchase Format.
- ➤ GST Receivable and payable format.
- Related party consolidates and balance confirmation.

Audit and Finalization:

- Design questionnaires to gather needed data for audit procedures.
- > Reach out to clients medical and financial groups for information.
- Manage audit files in computer and paper form.
- Consult with auditors to determine needed support activities.
- Retrieve information for auditors and assistants to facilitate timely completion of projects.

Transport Cost:

Preparation and analysis of transport cost.
 (Running KM,KM cost per vehicle, Calculation for Vehicle Depreciation).

Linguistic abilities

- To Speak ,Read, Write Tamil, English
- ➤ To Speak Telugu, Kannada

Personal Details

Date of Birth : 15, September, 1992
Gender : Male / Unmarried
Fathers Name : R.Gunasekaran
Mothers Name : G.Vasanthamani

Permanent Address : No.182A, Thuthariplayam, Kallipalayam post,

Palladam, Thiruppur Vattam, Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu.

Nationality / Religion : Indian / Hindu

Passport No : L2166820 (2013-2023)

Declaration

I hereby declare that the information's furnished above are true and correct to the best of my knowledge.

Place:	With Regards,
Date:	

(NAVEEN KUMAR.G)